const e="insurance",o=200,a=50,i=[{id:1,question:"Which of the following policies will prevent loss of home if the wage earner dies?",option:{a:"Term assurance",b:"Endowment assurance",c:"Mortgage insurance",d:"Whole life assurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:2,question:"One of the objectives of buying a term assurance policy is to",option:{a:"protect  dependants  in  case  of  death  of  the  life assured",b:"reduce financial burden of the life assured",c:"supplement retirement income  of  the  life  assured",d:"maximize savings from the life assured"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:3,question:"An assurance policy taken by experts to cover possible negligence arising from their duties is",option:{a:"consequential loss",b:"professional indemnity",c:"cargo",d:"freight"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:4,question:"The class of insurance that  covers  legal  liability to a third party for bodily injury and property damage caused by goods supplied is",option:{a:"employerâ€™s liability",b:"public liability",c:"professional indemnity",d:"products liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:5,question:"The  type  of  cover  that  is  designed  against  loss  of earnings following loss caused by fire and special perils is",option:{a:"product guarantee insurance",b:"materials damage cover",c:"fire damage policy",d:"consequential loss cover"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:6,question:"Which  of  the  following  risks  is  covered  by  insurance policy?",option:{a:"An investment loss on the stock market",b:"Dishonesty of an employee leading to fraud",c:"Failure of a business venture",d:"Rise and fall of prices of goods in the market"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:7,question:"In  classification  of  risks, what is the name given to a risk  where  the  causes  of  events are linked to factors 	that are due to the society we live in?",option:{a:"Dynamic risk",b:"Particular risk",c:"Speculative risk",d:"Fundamental risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:8,question:"The evidence of the insurance contract is",option:{a:"proposal form",b:"policy",c:"schedule",d:"endorsement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:9,question:"The right of the insurer to step in place of the insured for the purpose of recovering damages is called",option:{a:"representation",b:"indemnity",c:"subrogation",d:"contribution"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:10,question:"Which of the following is a contract of benefit?",option:{a:"Personal accident insurance",b:"Business interruption insurance",c:"Fire insurance",d:"Money insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:11,question:"Which of the following is not a feature of insurable interest?",option:{a:"Loss suffered",b:"subject matter",c:"Legal relationship",d:"Financial value"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:12,question:"A prospective insured in an engineering insurance may be advised to purchase one of the following classes of insurance",option:{a:"fire cover",b:"boiler cover",c:"tempest cover",d:"equipment cover"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:13,question:"The class of non-life insurance policy where cover note is issued is",option:{a:"fire insurance",b:"burglary insurance",c:"motor insurance",d:"fidelity guarantee"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:14,question:"Abandonment is mostly applicable to",option:{a:"marine insurance",b:"motor insurance",c:"fire insurance",d:"engineering insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:15,question:"Which of the following is not a benefit covered under a personal accident policy?",option:{a:"Death",b:"Temporary disablement",c:"Loss of baggage",d:"Medical expenses"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:16,question:"In the preparation of food for eat - in - customers, the cooks made a mistake in using excess quantity of an 	ingredient. A customer ate and  suffered  poisoning. 	Which policy of the operator would pick this liability?",option:{a:"Public liability",b:"Personal liability",c:"All risks insurance",d:"Loss of profit insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:17,question:"How much premium will the insurer charge?",option:{a:"N= 3,750",b:"N= 13,750",c:"N= 17,500",d:"N= 31,250"},section:"XYC Industries Limited proposed a fire risk to Adequate Insurance Plc. on a total sum insured of N= 5,000,000.00. The risk was accepted on a premium rate of 0.35%. After survey, the insurer charged a rate of 0.275%.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:18,question:"How  much  premium  will  the  insurer  return  to  the insured?",option:{a:"N= 3,750",b:"N= 13,750",c:"N= 17,500",d:"N= 31,250"},section:"XYC Industries Limited proposed a fire risk to Adequate Insurance Plc. on a total sum insured of N= 5,000,000.00. The risk was accepted on a premium rate of 0.35%. After survey, the insurer charged a rate of 0.275%.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:19,question:"A policy that combines cover for many perils as a single policy  to  suit  the  insurance  needs of  an insured is",option:{a:"accident policy",b:"protection policy",c:"paternal policy",d:"packaged policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:20,question:"A residential building built beside a petrol filling station is described as a",option:{a:"risk",b:"hazard",c:"peril",d:"liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:21,question:"The document that sets out the list of items covered in insurance is a",option:{a:"manifest",b:"bill of lading",c:"policy list",d:"policy specification or form"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:22,question:"One of the information contained in a motor insurance cover note is the",option:{a:"behaviour of the insured",b:"occupation of the insured",c:"commencement date",d:"previous and present insurance history"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:23,question:"In property insurance, which of the following is not a direct loss?",option:{a:"Reinstating the property destroyed",b:"Replacing the property destroyed",c:"Repairing the property damaged",d:"Replacing third party property damaged"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:24,question:"Ade insured his property for N= 350,000.00. The property is subject to average condition. He suffered a loss amounting to N= 30,000.00 with the value of the property at the time of loss to be N= 370,000.00. How much will the insurer pay?",option:{a:"N= 14,583.33",b:"N= 28,378.38",c:"N= 30,000.00",d:"N= 31,714.29"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:25,question:"A method of providing indemnity in the event of loss is",option:{a:"cash payment",b:"professional advice",c:"resolution of dispute",d:"resolution of policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:26,question:"An insurer who buys reinsurance cover is insured as",option:{a:"retrocession",b:"retrocedant",c:"cession",d:"cadent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:27,question:"One of the information contained in a renewal notice is the",option:{a:"previous losses",b:"location of the risk",c:"occupation of the insured",d:"sum insured"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:28,question:"Family income option in a life policy provides that",option:{a:"the beneficiary will be paid for life",b:"the beneficiary receives the policy sum",c:"interest will be added monthly",d:"salary will be paid to the insured until death"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:29,question:"A provision in a policy that exempts an insurer from liability if the loss is less than a certain amount is",option:{a:"excess",b:"transfer",c:"lay days",d:"franchise"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:30,question:"Which of the following policies is a peril covered under a standard fire policy?",option:{a:"Lightning",b:"Storm",c:"Civil commotion",d:"Escape of oil"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:31,question:"A type of reinsurance where cession and acceptance is obligatory is",option:{a:"treaty",b:"captive",c:"facultative",d:"retrocession"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:32,question:"A contract sold  by  insurance companies that  pay  a monthly or  quarterly income  benefit for the  life  of a person is",option:{a:"endowment",b:"annuity",c:"income",d:"freight"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:33,question:"George effected two personal accident policies. The first policy provides N= 25,000.00 cover for loss of limb. The second policy provides N= 30,000.00 cover for loss of limb. What is the total amount that  George  will receive in the event of a valid loss of limb claim?",option:{a:"N= 5,000.00",b:"N= 25,000.00",c:"N= 30,000.00",d:"N= 55,000.00"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:34,question:"Renewal notice is  used by  insurers  to  remind the insured of the",option:{a:"reduction of cover",b:"continuation of cover",c:"expiration of cover",d:"increase of cover"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:35,question:"Risk Net Insurance Brokers Limited placed a business with an insurance company, in return the broker will be entitled to",option:{a:"fees",b:"commission",c:"profit",d:"revenue"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:36,question:"The professional service required for effective claims administration by insurers would be provided by",option:{a:"loss assessors",b:"risk managers",c:"loss adjusters",d:"claims consultants"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:37,question:"Which  of the following activities is  not a  function of the  Chartered  Insurance  Institute  of  Nigeria?",option:{a:"Setting a standard for members",b:"Promoting Professional growth",c:"Promoting the interest of insurers",d:"Specifying professional qualification"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:38,question:"Effective supervision and licensing of insurance firms in Nigeria is the function of",option:{a:"National Insurance Commission",b:"Institute of Loss Adjusters of Nigeria",c:"Chartered Insurance Institute of Nigeria",d:"Nigerian Corporation of Registered Insurance Brokers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:39,question:"The payment made when the insured is  not  entitled to claim under a policy is",option:{a:"voluntary excess",b:"ex-gratia",c:"return premium",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:40,question:"The owner of a life assurance policy who enters into an agreement to sell the ownership of the policy and beneficiary rights upon the death of the insured is called",option:{a:"an underwriter",b:"a aviator",c:"a factor",d:"an assessor"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:41,question:"A small fixed sum retained by the insured in the form of a claim is",option:{a:"slip",b:"severity",c:"excess",d:"frequency"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:42,question:"A voucher signed by the insured before collecting his claim is",option:{a:"money collect receipt",b:"discharge voucher",c:"payment receipt",d:"pay - in - slip"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:43,question:"To which of the following parties does the principle of utmost good faith apply in a contract of insurance?",option:{a:"The proposer only",b:"The insurer only",c:"The insurer and proposer",d:"The third party and insured"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:44,question:"Insurers A and B cover a risk at the ratio of 2:5 for the sum insured of N= 1,800. How much would insurer  A get from the risk?",option:{a:"N= 1,285.00",b:"N= 771.00",c:"N= 514.00",d:"N= 180.00"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:45,question:"The consideration paid for insurance contract is",option:{a:"money",b:"commission",c:"premium",d:"fee"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:46,question:"The alternative to seeking for surrender value in a life assurance contract is",option:{a:"automatic non - forfeiture",b:"revival condition",c:"paid-up policy",d:"standing order"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:47,question:"Which of the following is a risk covered in endowment assurance?",option:{a:"Permanent disability",b:"Bodily injury",c:"Temporary disability",d:"Death cover"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:48,question:"A <em>revival clause</em> in a life policy will allow an insured to revive a policy that lapsed on account of nonpayment of premium, provided the insured",option:{a:"can prove he is sick at the time",b:"cannot fall sick after the policy",c:"can prove he is in good health",d:"can recover from the ill health"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:49,question:"Which of  the  following  risks  are  covered  under engineering insurance?",option:{a:"Material damage and liability cover",b:"Boiler and special perils cover",c:"Computer and explosion cover",d:"Property damage and business interruption cover"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:50,question:"Which of the following is not a function of an insurance broker?",option:{a:"Assisting clients in paying premium",b:"Maintaining proper records of claims",c:"Assisting clients in connecting to insurers",d:"Assisting clients in effecting uninsured loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"}],s={subject:e,status:200,total:50,data:i};export{i as data,s as default,o as status,e as subject,a as total};
